你的说话方式会让别人判断你是什么样的人。注意不要透露出一种
How you talk indicates to people how you are. Beware of revealing a personality
并不属于你的性格。语调没有绝对的对错，
that you don't have. There is no absolute right or wrong in regard to intonation
因为几乎任何一个词或音节都可以找到理由去重读，但你
because a case can be made for stressing just about any word or syllable, but you
选择强调哪些元素，实际上会透露出很多关于你自己的信息。比如，
actually reveal a lot about yourself by the elements you choose to emphasize. For
如果你说 hello，这种语调会表示怀疑。你会这样说
example, if you say, hello, this intonation would indicate doubt. You say
hello 来接电话，因为你不知道电话另一头是谁。或者当
hello when answering the phone because you don't know who's on the other end. Or when
你走进一栋房子，看不到任何人，也不知道里面是谁。
you go into a house and you don't know who's there because you don't see anyone.
但如果你在演讲或做展示，站到
But if you're giving a speech or making a presentation and you stand up in front of
人群面前说 hello，大家很可能会笑，因为它听起来太
a crowd and say hello, the people would probably laugh because it sounds so
不确定。这时你应该自信地说：hello，my name is so-and-so。
uncertain. This is where you'd confidently want to say hello, my name is so-and-so. A
第二个例子是两种 my name is 重音位置的对比。后一种听起来像是
second example is my name is as opposed to my name is. It sounds as if you're going
继续说出更多个人信息：My name is so-and-so，my
to continue with more personal information. My name is so-and-so, my
address is such-and-such，my blood type is O。既然你可能并不想
address is such-and-such, my blood type is O. Since it may not be your intention to
说出全部信息，就保持标准说法：hello，my name is so-and-so。如果
give all that information, stay with the standard, hello, my name is so-and-so. If
你每次都重读 I，就会显得你自我评价很高。
you stress I every time, it will seem that you have a very high opinion of yourself.
试试看下面这段，注意不同语气：
Try it. I'm taking American accent training. I've been paying attention to
pitch too。I think I'm quite wonderful。一个认真、努力的人可能会
pitch, too. I think I'm quite wonderful. An earnest, hard-working person might
这样强调词语。比如：
emphasize words this way. I'm taking American accent training. Can I learn this
必要时，我会强迫自己享受其中。
stuff? I hope to make it as enjoyable as possible. I'll force myself to enjoy it if
虽然唯一掌握它的方法，是每天 24 小时不停练习。
I have to, although the only way to get it is to practice all the time, 24 hours a
day。一个怀疑型的人则会这样表现：I should pick up on the
day. A doubting Thomas would show up with, I should pick up on the
American intonation pattern pretty easily。可是它看起来也挺难。
American intonation pattern pretty easily, but it looks pretty hard, too.
最近我和很多美国人聊天，他们说我更容易被
I've been talking to a lot of Americans lately, and they tell me that I'm easier
听懂，但我认为他们只是很礼貌。
to understand, but I think they're just being polite.